今天给虫教你开锁
Today, I'm going to show you how to pick a padlock
科普一下 视频中演示的是我们国家的A级锁
A级锁是所有锁里最好开的
视频中的一字钥匙锁头熟练的人几秒就能打开
因此这种锁头相当不安全
并用这个透明的锁带你了解开锁的时候锁的内部发生了什么
and to help you see what's going on, we're going to use this clear transparent padlock
当钥匙插入锁芯时，大家可以看到钥匙的形状是如何提升六个“外弹子”的
If we push the key into the lock mechanism, you can see how the profile of the key lifts all six pins into alignment
这样，锁芯就能转动，锁就能打开了
allowing the cylinder to be turned, and the lock to be opened
从另一侧看，当我转动锁芯时，你可以看到内锁芯的六个“内弹子”
If I show you again from the other side, when I rotate the cylinder, you can see all six of the bottom key pins
六个内弹子需要抬起到准确位置才能让锁芯旋转
which need to be raised to exactly the right point to lift the upper pins above the shear point
to allow the cylinder to turn
当我拔出钥匙，弹簧就会将外弹子推进内锁芯，让内锁芯无法旋转
As I remove the key, the springs push the upper pins back into the cylinder
and lock it into position, stopping it from turning
想要不用钥匙开锁，我买了一套开锁工具
To open the padlock without a key, I bought a set of these lock picks
整套家伙事挺齐全的
The set comes with a whole host of different picks to try and master
当中很多的开锁工具
And also, a number of these tension tools
外形非常相似，但形状大小有很微小的差异
these all look very similar, but actually have very slight differences in size or shape
想要开锁，第一步是先把这个工具卡在锁的底部
To pick the lock, the idea is to insert one of these tension tools into the bottom of the lock here
然后对锁芯施加一个旋转的力量
and apply a small amount of tension or torsion to the cylinder
可以像我这样一只手同时拿住锁并且掰着这个工具
You need to do this with one hand, while holding the lock as well
然后拿出开锁工具
then take a lock pick
然后需要尝试升起每一个内弹子使外弹子高于内外锁芯的分界
and we need to try and lift each pin so that the upper pin is above the shear line
刚刚施加的旋转力量可以卡住外弹子，使其不会被弹簧顶回
Maintaining a small amount of torsion on the cylinder will stop the pins from falling back down
同时还要小心别把内弹子抬太高
You need to also be careful not to lift the lower pins above the shear line
因为这样也会让锁芯无法转动
as this will also prevent the cylinder from being able to turn
当所有弹子都被提升到正确高度时
When they're all set at the correct height
你会感觉你最开始旋转的阻力变小
you should be able to feel the resistance on the torsion tool diminish
此时锁就能打开了
and now you're able to turn the cylinder and open the shackle
技能点+1
Pretty cool, huh?
我再演示一遍，这个需要很多练习的
I'll show you again. It does take quite a bit of practice
但当你找到感觉后，一条致富的道路就摆在你面前了→_→
but you really get a feel for what's going on, and it is possible to pick the lock quite quickly
如果我们转动锁芯时看锁的另一面
If I show you the other side of the lock as I twist the cylinder
你依然可以看见六个内弹子
again, you can see all six of the lower pins
如果我用开锁工具在里面瞎捅，你也能看到内弹子们在上下移动
and if I run the pick underneath them you can see them moving up and down
当我把锁芯转回原位时，外弹子弹回，重新锁住锁芯
When I lined the cylinder back up, the top pins drop back, and lock in place
尝试开这东西还是挺有趣的
It's a really good, fun puzzle to try and crack
你还可以试试一套里的其他工具，看看哪个更顺手
You can try out different picks, and see which one works best for you
当然，用透明的锁会给人一种钦定的感觉，那换个真锁试试吧
But of course, using a transparent lock is cheating a bit, so get yourself a real padlock, and see how you get on
当你真打开的时候，成就感满满呀
When you do eventually crack it, it's really satisfying
你可以用之前的工具一个一个抬内弹子，还可以试试这个工具，在锁芯里乱捅
You can try lifting individual pins at a time, or try using a rake, like this, to rake the lock
我希望大家喜欢这个视频，更多相关内容请关注原YouTuber
I hope you've enjoyed watching this video, if you want to see more of my lock related videos
原YouTuber频道名“DaveHax”，欢迎过去围观
you can click on the links, or take a look at my YouTube channel page
字幕翻译给虫，主要翻译航空航天科普视频
and if you want to be notified every time I launch a new video
欢迎点赞投币关注收藏分享
you need to subscribe to my channel, then click the little notification bell by the subscribe button, and tick the box
感谢观看
Have fun, stay safe, and as always, thanks for watching! (Subtitles By SebastienGaming SG)